seattleclouds.com 2019-07-25

# Build Native iPhone APPS - EASY, RELIABLE, EXTENSIBLE

**Privacy Policy**

**MOBILESOFT TECHNOLOGY INC. PRIVACY POLICY**

**UPDATED: JUNE 18, 2018**

Welcome to MobileSoft Technology, Inc. (" **MobileSoft** ", " **we** " " **our** " or " **us** "), a Delaware corporation. We respect and protect the privacy of our customers and those who use our services.

This Privacy Policy governs your use of our websites (the " **Websites** ") our mobile and desktop apps (the " **Apps** ") and all related sites, products, players, widgets, tools, apps, data, software, APIs and other services provided by MobileSoft (collectively, the " **Services** "), and is in addition to (not in lieu of) any specific privacy terms that apply to the particular Services you purchase or access through our Websites or Apps. 

Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, store, use and disclose your personal information when you use our Services. Personal information is any information that identifies you or would enable someone to contact you, such as your name, email address, phone number and other non-public information that is associated with the foregoing.

By using our Services, and in particular by registering an account, you agree that you have read and understand this Privacy Policy and are consenting to the use of your personal information in the manner set out in this Privacy Policy. Please take some time to read this Privacy Policy and make sure you are comfortable with our use of your personal information. If you do not agree to any of the provisions of this Privacy Policy, you should not use the Services. If you have any questions or concerns, you can contact us at [sc.support@mobilesoft.com](mailto:support@mobilesoft.com).

Please note that this Privacy Policy only applies to the Websites, Apps and the Services (together, the " **Platform** ") provided by us. When using the Platform, you may find links to other websites, apps and services, or tools that enable you to provide information to other websites, apps and services. MobileSoft is not responsible for the privacy practices of those other websites, apps or services, and we recommend that you review the privacy policies of each of those websites, apps or services before connecting your MobileSoft account or providing any personal information.

**Our Principles**

We have a very simple approach to data protection and privacy, which is that:

  * You should know exactly what we do with your personal information; and

  * You should have full control over your personal information.

This Privacy Policy is designed to give you full transparency regarding our data protection practices. If there is anything that is not clear from this Privacy Policy, please feel free to email us at [sc.support@mobilesoft.com](mailto:support@mobilesoft.com).

We have designed the Platform to give you control over the information you provide using the Platform and other websites and services to which you connect your Platform account. Please take full advantage of these tools and make sure you only provide information or content that you want to provide.

**Information we collect about you**

We collect personal information about you from various sources, such as:

(a) Information provided by you:

You do not need to provide us with any personal information in order to visit our Websites. However, certain Services do require that you register for an account and, by doing so, you will provide us with certain personal information:

(i) Essential Information: When users create any kind of Platform account, we ask for information such as your name, organization name, mobile phone number, email address, billing address, and credit card information.

(ii) Profile Information: For your profile on the Platform you must provide a user name. You may choose, at your discretion, to provide additional information for your profile. For example:

  * Your real name

  * A profile picture or avatar

  * Information about you

  * Your interests

  * Your website

  * Your blog

None of this profile information is mandatory and any information you do provide may be deleted, edited, changed or amended by you at any time. For more information, see the "Choice and Control" section below

(b) Information from correspondence:    
You will provide certain personal information if you contact us by email, use any of the web forms on the Websites, or contact us by mail, fax or other offline means.

(c) Survey Information: If you participate in any survey, you will provide certain personal information as part of your response, unless you respond anonymously.

(d) Information that you post: You may provide personal information when you upload content to the Platform, or when you post comments, or contribute to community discussions.

(e) Information we collect automatically: There is certain information that we collect automatically as the result of your use of the Platform or through the use of web analytics services. This information includes:

(i) The Internet Protocol (IP) address of the device from which you access the Platform (this can sometimes be used to derive the country or city from which you are accessing the Platform)

(ii) The website that you visited immediately prior to visiting our Website

(iii) The specific actions that you take on the Platform, including the pages that you visit, activities that you perform on the Platform, connecting your Facebook or other accounts, posting a comment, performing a search, and other activities which may be made available from time to time.

(iv) Any search terms that you may enter on the Platform

(v) The time, frequency and duration of your visits to the Platform

(vi) Your browser type and operating system

(vii) The nature of the device from which you are accessing the Platform, for example, whether you are accessing the Platform from a personal computer or from a mobile device

(viii) Information collected through cookies and similar technology

**Information from Other Sources**

Some of our Websites, allow you to sign up and log in using your Facebook or Google+ account. If you sign up using Facebook, Facebook will ask your permission to share certain information from your Facebook account with the Platform. This includes your public profile, email address and user friends. If you sign up using Google+, Google+ will receive your first name, last name, and email address.

This information is collected by Facebook and Google+ and is provided to us under the terms of [ _Facebook's privacy policy_](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)  and [ _Google's privacy policy_](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). You can control the information that we receive from Facebook and Google+ using the privacy settings in your Facebook and Google+ account.

If you sign up to use the Platform using Facebook, your account will be connected automatically to your Facebook account, and information regarding your activity on the Platform will be shared with Facebook and may be published in your timeline and your Facebook friends' newsfeeds. If you do not wish to share your activity with your Facebook friends, you can control this from the Settings page on the Website. For more information, see the "Choice and Control" section below. If you signed up using Facebook by mistake, you can delete your account from the Account page within your Settings at any time, or you can email us at [sc.support@mobilesoft.com](mailto:support@mobilesoft.com).

**How we use your personal information**

We use the information that we collect about you for the following purposes:

  * Your email address and password are used to identify you when you log into the Platform.

  * Any additional information that you provide as part of your public profile, such as your real name and links to your website will be published on your profile page. This information will be publicly accessible and may be viewed by anyone accessing the Website, or using our Apps or other Services. Please bear this in mind when considering whether to provide any additional information about yourself.

  * If you subscribe to a premium account, your name, address and payment verification information will be used to process your account subscription and to collect your payment. All payment verification information is transmitted using industry-standard SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. MobileSoft also complies with the Payment Card Industry Security Standards.

  * Your email address will be used to send you service updates and notifications regarding your account, and (if you have elected to receive them using your account preferences) newsletters, marketing messages and certain email notifications. For information about how to change your preferences, and to unsubscribe from newsletters, marketing messages and email notifications. Please see the "Choice and Control" section below.

Your personal information is also used for the following general purposes:

  * To operate and maintain your Platform account, and to provide you with access to the Website and use of the Apps and any Services that you may request from time to time.

  * To seek your participation in surveys, and to conduct and analyze the results of those surveys, if you choose to participate.

  * To provide you with technical support.

  * To analyze the use of the Platform, the people visiting the Website and their use of the Apps and Services, in order to improve the Platform.

  * To respond to you about any comment or enquiry you have submitted.

  * To customize your use of the Platform and/or the content of any email newsletter or other material that we may send to you from time to time.

  * To consider you for receipt of certain advertisements which may be of interest to you.

  * To prevent or take action against activities that are, or may be, in breach of our Terms of Use or applicable law.

  * For other purposes, provided we disclose it to you at the relevant time, and provided you agree to the proposed use of the relevant personal information.

**Security of Information**

We take appropriate technical and organizational measures and reasonable steps to protect your personal information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction, but do not and cannot guarantee such protection. Please bear in mind that transmissions over the Internet are not completely secure, and any information you send to or from our Services may be accessible by others. More specifically, email sent to or from our Services may not be secure. As a result, you should take particular care in deciding what information you send via email. Any passwords, ID numbers, or other special access numbers you might use to access any part of our Services are your responsibility; take care to safeguard them.

**Sharing of your personal information**

We will not share your personal information with any third party, except as described in this Privacy Policy. There are circumstances where we may need to share some of the personal information we collect about you or which you provide to us. Those circumstances are as follows:

_Other Users:_  Any personal information in your public profile (other than your email address) will be accessible by other users of the Platform who may view your profile information.

_With your consent:_  We will disclose your personal information if you have explicitly agreed that we may do so. We will make this clear to you at the point at which we collect your information.

_Service Providers:_  We use reputable third parties to provide us with certain specialized services related to the Platform. These third parties will have access to certain information about you, but only where this is necessary in order for those third parties to provide their services to us. Where we transfer personal information to these third parties, we require these third parties to implement appropriate organizational and technical security measures to protect against unauthorized disclosure of personal information, and only to process personal information in accordance with our instructions and to the extent necessary to provide their services to us.

_Other networks and connected apps:_  If you choose to connect your Platform account to other apps or social networks such as Facebook and Google+ you will be sharing certain information with these apps or networks. MobileSoft is not responsible for these other apps or networks, so please make sure you only connect your account with apps or services that you trust. For information on how to control the information that you provide, and how to disconnect your account from other networks or apps, please see the "Choice and Control" section below.

_As aggregated data:_  We may aggregate your personal data with similar data relating to other users of the Platform in order to create statistical information regarding the Platform and its use, which we may then share with third parties or make publicly available. However, no such information will include any email address or other contact information, or anything that could be used to identify you individually, either online or in real life.

_If required by law:_  We will disclose your personal information if we believe in good faith that we are permitted or required to do so by law, including in response to a court order, subpoena or other legal demand or request.

_To protect our interests:_  We may disclose your personal information if we feel this is necessary in order to protect or defend our legitimate rights and interests, or those of our users, employees, directors or shareholders, and/or to ensure the safety and security of the Platform and/or the user community.

_In the context of a business transfer:_  We may transfer your personal information to any person or company that acquires all or substantially all of the assets or business of MobileSoft, or on a merger of our business, or in the event of our insolvency.

**Choice and Control**

We do our best to give you as much choice as possible regarding the amount of personal information you provide to us and the control you have over that information. It is not necessary for you to provide us with any information in order to visit our Websites, although certain information will be collected automatically by virtue of your visit (as described above). However, if you do decide to register a Platform account, you can control your personal information as described below.

**Email preferences**

Users will receive platform notifications to the email address on file.

Users may unsubscribe from email newsletters at any time by clicking on the link at the end of each email.

**Sharing with other apps and networks**

If you sign up for the Platform using your Facebook account, your Platform account and your Facebook account will be connected automatically, and information regarding your activity on the Platform will be shared with Facebook and may appear on your timeline and in your Facebook friends' newsfeeds. If you do not want this information shared with Facebook, please change your Settings. Please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to any third-party sites or applications, and we cannot control the activities of those sites or applications. You are advised to read the privacy policies of those sites or applications before sharing your information with, or connecting your Platform account to, any of these third-party sites or applications.

**Cookies**

Like most other websites, we use cookies and similar technologies to help us understand how people view and use our Websites so that we can keep improving our Platform.  **If you choose to use the Platform without blocking or disabling cookies or opting out of other technologies, you will have indicated your consent to our use of cookies and other technologies and to our use (in accordance with this cookie policy and the rest of this Privacy Policy) of any personal information that we collect using these technologies. If you do not consent to the use of these technologies, please be sure to block or disable them using your browser settings or the settings within our mobile apps.**

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. These text files can be read by these websites and help to identify you when you return to a website. Cookies can be "persistent" or "session" cookies. Persistent cookies remain on your computer when you have gone offline, while session cookies are deleted as soon as you close your web browser.

To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to block and delete cookies, please visit [ _http://www.aboutcookies.org/_](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

We use our own cookies to recognize you when you visit our Website or use our Apps. This means that you don't have to log in each time you visit, and we can remember your preferences and settings.

In addition to our own cookies, we work with various reputable companies to help us analyze how the Platform is used, and to optimize our Websites and Apps to deliver the best possible experience.

We think it's important that you are able to control the collection of personal data relating to your use of MobileSoft and have therefore made sure that you can opt out of any personal data collection using cookies or other technologies as set out below.

You can use the settings within your browser to control the cookies that are set on your computer or mobile device. However, please be aware that cookies are important to many aspects for the Platform - if you set your browser to reject cookies, you may not be able to enjoy all of the features of the Platform. To find out how to see what cookies have been set and how to reject and delete cookies, please visit [ _http://www.aboutcookies.org_](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

**Deleting your account**

You can delete your account from Settings section on the Platform at any time. Please bear in mind that, if you delete your account, all data associated with your account will be deleted and may not be recoverable. You are therefore advised to copy or back up all content uploaded to your account before you delete your account.

Even if you delete your Platform account, it is possible that your information may still show up in some internet search results for a short while afterwards, if the search engine maintains a temporary cache of web pages. Search engines' caching processes are outside of MobileSoft's control and therefore we cannot be responsible for any information that remains cached by search engines after that information has been removed from the Platform.

Please note that deleting any MobileSoft Apps, or any third-party apps to which your Platform account is connected, will not delete your Platform account. If you wish to delete your account, you will need to do so from the tab in your Settings on the Platform. Similarly, if you delete a third-party app that is connected to your Platform account over our API, this will not necessarily delete all data from within that third-party app. You will need to refer to the app provider's terms of use and privacy policy to find out how to delete your data from that third-party app.

**Access to your Data**

As described above, most of the personal information you provide to us can be accessed and updated in the Settings page of your Platform account. If you wish to access, amend or delete any other personal information we hold about you, or if you have any objection to the processing of any information that we hold about you, please contact us at [sc.support@mobilesoft.com](mailto:support@mobilesoft.com), or the address provided below. Anything that cannot be changed is deemed required by MobileSoft. If you feel you are not comfortable with this information being used by MobileSoft, please delete your account and cease using the Services.

If you ask us to delete your account (either via the Settings page or by email), we will do so within a reasonable period of time, but we may need to retain some of your personal information in order to satisfy our legal obligations, or where we have a legitimate reason for doing so.

**International data transfers**

MobileSoft is based in the United States and your personal information is collected, stored and used in accordance with U.S. laws. However, from time to time, it may be necessary for us to transfer your personal information outside the U.S. You should be aware that privacy laws in the location where we may transfer your data may not be equivalent to the laws of the United States. By using the Platform you consent to the transfer, storage and processing of your personal information outside the United States in accordance with this Privacy Policy and applicable law.

**Children**

Our Services are not intended for use by children. Anyone under the age of 16 is not permitted to use the Platform and must not attempt to register an account or submit any personal information to us. We do not knowingly collect any personal information from any person who is under the age of 16. If it comes to our attention that we have collected personal data from a person under the age of 16, we will delete this information as quickly as possible. If you have reason to believe that we may have collected any such data, please notify us immediately at [sc.support@mobilesoft.com](mailto:support@mobilesoft.com).

**MobileSoft does not support DNT**

At this time our Websites do not recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking mechanisms, which may include 'do not track' instructions. However, you can change your privacy preferences regarding the use of cookies and similar technologies through your browser. You may set your browser to accept all cookies, block certain cookies, require your consent before a cookie is placed in your browser, or block all cookies. Please consult the 'Help' section of your browser for more information.

**Special Notification for California Residents**

Individual users of our Services who reside in California and have provided their personal information to us may request information about our disclosures of certain categories of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Such requests must be submitted to us at one of the following addresses: e-mail to sc.support@mobilesoft.com, or write to us at: MobileSoft, Attn: Legal Department, 120 South 6th Street Suite 900, Minneapolis, MN 55402.

Within thirty days of receiving such a request, we will provide a list of the categories of personal information disclosed to third parties for third-party direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, along with the names and addresses of these third parties. This request may be made no more than once per calendar year. We reserve our right not to respond to requests submitted other than to the address specified in this paragraph.

**No Error-Free Performance**

We do not guarantee error-free performance under this Privacy Policy. We may not always catch an unintended privacy issue, despite our efforts to do so. We will use reasonable efforts to comply with this Privacy Policy and will take prompt corrective action when we learn of any failure to comply with it. Accordingly, we welcome your feedback regarding any privacy concerns.

**Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy**

We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy, and when we do so, we will also revise the Effective Date set out below. Any changes to our Privacy Policy will always be available here so that Platform users are always aware of what information we gather, and how we might use and share that information. Please be sure to check back here from time to time to ensure that you are aware of any changes to this Privacy Policy. Any material changes to this Privacy Policy will be communicated to registered users by a notification to their account and/or by posting a notice of the change on the Platform.

**Questions**

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, want to suggest changes to this Privacy Policy or want to know, what information we store about you, please contact us by email at [sc.support@mobilesoft.com](mailto:support@mobilesoft.com), or write to us at: MobileSoft, Attn: Legal Department, 120 South 6th Street Suite 900, Minneapolis, MN 55402.

**Don't want to give us your information?**

If you decide that you do not want us to use your personal information in the manner described in the Privacy Policy, please do not use the Platform.

**Effective Date:**  June 18, 2018
